<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enhanced Aerobic Bio-remediation of Chlorinated Solvents using VaporRemed - Field Report. Sarva Bio Remed, LLC.</title>
    <link>https://dservgun.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Enhanced Aerobic Bio-remediation of Chlorinated Solvents using VaporRemed - Field Report. Sarva Bio Remed, LLC.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dservgun.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of TCE decay.</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/decaycurveanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/decaycurveanalysis/</guid>
      <description>First-order decay curves at SG-106 Here we focus on the project period between 12/4/2019 - 12/14/2019. The image shown below for the degradation of TCE/PCE levels after adding VaporRemed on 12/4/2019.
These numbers allowed us to extrapolate a decay model for TCE based on the PCE data (an approximate second-order derivative). The image shown below shows an increase in TCE before falling off to a straight-line first-order decay.
The curve shown above indicates that TCE levels increase before they decrease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Aerobic bio-remediation of Chlorinated Solvents at a strip mall in York, PA</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/summary/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Aerobic Bio-remediation Report Introduction In this report, we present data collected on aerobicbio-remediation of soil contaminated with Perchloroethene (PCE), Trichloroethene (TCE), cis-1,2-Dichloroethene (cis12DCE) and Vinyl Chloride (VC) using VaporRemed.
Enhanced Aerobic Bio-remediation of Chlorintaed Hydrocarbons The reference, In Situ Bioremediaton : When Does It Work?, lists at least three criteria for demonstrating that in situ bio-remediation is effective for a given project:
 Documented loss of contaminants from the site due to bio-remediation, Labotary assays showing that the micro-organisms in site samples have the potential to transform contaminants under expected site condition, and One or more pieces of evidence showing that the bio-remediation potential is actually realized in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location details</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/locationdetails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/locationdetails/</guid>
      <description>Location details. Here are some images to help gain a perspective about the project.
Mall&amp;rsquo;s front Loading dock Geo probe Addition of AgroRemed </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VaporRemed Facts</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/vaporremedfactfigures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/vaporremedfactfigures/</guid>
      <description>Total amount of VaporRemed added to Soil - 41 gallons. Total amount of VaporRemed added to Sub-slab area - 142 + 91 = 233 gallons. Total amount of VaporRemed added to SG-101 - 35 gallons Total amount of VaporRemed added to SG-106 - 100 gallons. Grand total amount of VaporRemed added to the site is - 476 gallons. Comparison with other projects Although to do an apples-to-apples comparison is not accurate, the following paragraph from the Fourth Five-Year Review Report for Middlefield-Ellis-Whisman (MEW) Superfund Study Area (Pg.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>