<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Bioremediation of Chlorinated Solvents - Blog</title>
    <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Bioremediation of Chlorinated Solvents - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>DeeAar Holdings, LLC. 2020, All Rights Reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 18:18:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://dservgun.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Abandoned Gas Station in Mays Landing, NJ</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/mayslanding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jan 2022 18:18:04 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/mayslanding/</guid>
      <description>Summary While there is some debate about the definition of abandoned gas stations as to how old does a gas station have to be operational to be declared as abandoned, we can generally agree with the notion that an abandoned gas station is presents a significant risk to the community.
What we do? We use bio-remediation products AgroRemed and HydroRemed as part of our cleanup protocol.
Results The tanks were removed in 2018, we closed this project on Jan 17th 2022.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RandomThoughts</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/randomthoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 10:06:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/randomthoughts/</guid>
      <description>Some thoughts on Haskell and purity. A friend of mine introduced me to CPS a few weeks ago and this got me interested in Andrew Appel&amp;rsquo;s Modern Compiler Implementation in ML that implements a compiler for Tiger programming language.
The chapter on Static-single assignment or SSA form was instructive because it offered an alternative perspective on why purity in functional languages matter. SSA is a property of an intermediate representation, that requires that each variable be assigned only once, and be defined before it is used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Energy Equation for Asphalt Shingles from FOWA Extraction Process</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/energyequationforasphaltshingles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 18:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/energyequationforasphaltshingles/</guid>
      <description>FOWA Extraction Process This post discusses the energy equation for the FOWA process based on some observations and assumptions. Briefly, the process allows an asphalt producer to extract bunker fuel - test 1, bunker fuel - test 2 - S - 441 ppm and bunker fuel - test3 - S - 291 ppm [from asphalt1. The links to tests 2 and tests 3 show that the sulfur content in the extracted oil is between 291 - 441 ppm less than the 5000 ppm (or 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Biodegradation of Polystyrene</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/polystyrenebiodegradation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 18:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/polystyrenebiodegradation/</guid>
      <description>A short paper on biodegradation of plastics using our products. Paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimates for production of ULSFO from waste asphalt</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/productionestimatesulsfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Jan 2021 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/productionestimatesulsfo/</guid>
      <description>Production estimates from Asphalt We were asked to put out some estimates on the amount of ULSFO from waste asphalt. This link contains a table that presents those estimates.
 TLDR; 100,000.00 kilograms of waste Asphalt is estimated to produce 90,000 liters.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Producing ULSFO (Ultra low sulfur fuel oil)</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/producingulfo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Dec 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/producingulfo/</guid>
      <description>Pitch deck for the process of generating fuel oil from asphalt shingles. I am trying something new, I am going to attach a presentation that I would like to take to angel investors. I would love to get some feedback to help me improve the deck. The deck is attached here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collection of current and past projects.</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/somecollectionsofcurrentprojects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 18:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/somecollectionsofcurrentprojects/</guid>
      <description>This document is a result of a recent conversation with an environmental consultant. They wanted to find out some schematics, flow diagrams of application of VaporRemed on the field. We have tried to collect them here. Link.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poster Presentation at AEHS</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/aehsposterpresentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Oct 2020 18:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/aehsposterpresentation/</guid>
      <description>We presented our findings at the 36th Conference on Water, Soil and Sediments hosted by AEHS. Here are links to the poster and the handout.
Notes We presented the poster virtually due to the ongoing pandemic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VaporRemed Facts</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/vaporremedfactfigures/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/vaporremedfactfigures/</guid>
      <description>Summary  The total amount of VaporRemed added to Soil - 41 gallons. The total amount of VaporRemed added to Sub-slab area - 142 + 91 = 233 gallons. The total amount of VaporRemed added to SG-101 - 35 gallons The total amount of VaporRemed added to SG-106 - 100 gallons.  The total amount of VaporRemed added to the site : 476 Gallons Comparison with other projects Although to do an apples-to-apples comparison is not accurate, the following paragraph from the Fourth Five-Year Review Report for Middlefield-Ellis-Whisman (MEW) Superfund Study Area (Pg.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vapor Attenuation</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/vaporattenuation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/vaporattenuation/</guid>
      <description>Vapor Attenuation of paired PCE values between Indoor Air (IA-001) and Sub-Slab area (VP-003) The plot below shows the VaporAttenuation factor based on the formula below for PCE values.
Notes We present vapor attenuation as a function of time to understand the impact of VaporRemed during the remediation process. Vapor attenuation (Johnson and Ettinger 1991) refers to the reduction in concentration of vapor-forming chemicals that occurs during vapor migration in the subsurface, coupled with the dilution that can occur when the vapors enter a building and mix with indoor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enhanced Aerobic bio-remediation of Chlorinated Solvents at a strip mall in York, PA</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/summary/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/summary/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced Aerobic Bio-remediation Report Introduction In this report, we present data collected on aerobicbio-remediation of soil contaminated with Perchloroethene (PCE), Trichloroethene (TCE), cis-1,2-Dichloroethene (cis12DCE) and Vinyl Chloride (VC) using VaporRemed.
Enhanced Aerobic Bio-remediation of Chlorintaed Hydrocarbons In Situ Bioremediaton : When Does It Work?, lists at least three criteria for demonstrating that in situ bio-remediation is effective for a given site:
 Documented loss of contaminants from the site due to bio-remediation, Laboratory assays showing that the micro-organisms in site samples have the potential to transform contaminants under expected site condition, and One or more pieces of evidence showing that the bio-remediation potential is actually realized in the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VaporRemed Case Studies</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/someoldpostsonvaporremed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/someoldpostsonvaporremed/</guid>
      <description>VaporRemed Case Studies A site in Virginia   A site in Virginia, one of our initial projects - circa 2006.   An image showing the earmarked area     An image showing the trenches below the AST     A detailed report of the project
  Some quotes and figures from the report   Groundwater results at MW-1 between 2005 - 2006   The application of AgroRemed appears to have reduced the levels of dissolved phase contamination in the groundwater and increased dispersion of the free product, resulting in an increase in the amount of free product in MW-4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Statement</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/missionstatement/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/missionstatement/</guid>
      <description>Mission statement - Evolving as we enhance our process to deal with various hydrocarbon contaminants Our mission is to help cleanup the mess created by fossil-fuels and dry-cleaning solvents such as Trichloroethylene (TCE), Perchloroethylene (PCE), asphalt and oil. Our mission is to cleanup of sites contaminated with dry cleaning chemicals such as PCE/TCE and also fuel oil releases in the environment effectively through aerobic bioremediation. Current cleanup methods are quite cumbersome and very expensive as they involve invasive process of excavation and disposal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plots of various locations</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/locationplots/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/locationplots/</guid>
      <description>Plots of contamination levels at various locations   Vapor Attenuation Curve between 2018 - 2020   IA-001 between 2018 - 2020   IA-002 between 2018 - 2020   IA-004 between 2018 - 2020   IA-007 between 2018 - 2020   IA-008 between 2018 - 2020   IA-009 between 2018 - 2020   IA-010 between 2018 - 2020   IA-011 between 2018 - 2019   SB-121 between Jun 2017 - Sept 2017   SG-106 between June 2019 - May 2020   SG-101 between June 2019 - May 2020   VP-003 between 2018 - 2020   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Location details</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/locationdetails/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/locationdetails/</guid>
      <description>Location details. Here are some images to help gain a perspective about the project.
Mall&amp;rsquo;s front Geo probe Addition of AgroRemed </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PCE levels in one of the hotspots - May 2020</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/indoorairlevels-may2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/indoorairlevels-may2020/</guid>
      <description>Update on the levels of PCE/TCE in Indoor Air (IA-001), SG-101 and SG-106 The current post presents the latest data recorded in indoor air in one of the hotspots, namely IA-001 in May 2020.
 IA-001  SG-101  SG-106   Note The increase in levels of 1,2-cisDCE and VinylChloride (VC) are indicative or bio-remediation of solvents accomplished by VaporRemed.
TCE levels at IA-001  IA-001  SG-106  SG-101 Even though we see a slight uptick, the numbers are still within the site-specific limits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of TCE decay.</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/decaycurveanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/decaycurveanalysis/</guid>
      <description>First-order decay curves at SG-106 Here we focus on the project period between 12/4/2019 - 12/14/2019. The image shown below for the degradation of TCE/PCE levels after adding VaporRemed on 12/4/2019.
These numbers allowed us to extrapolate a decay model for TCE based on the PCE data (an approximate second-order derivative). The image shown below shows an increase in TCE before falling off to a straight-line first-order decay.
The curve shown above indicates that TCE levels increase before they decrease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive IAQ Report</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/comprehensive-data-tables/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/comprehensive-data-tables/</guid>
      <description>Comprehensive IAQ Report We post a summary of the comprehensive report for the site between 2018 and 2020.
Report for 2020 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bacterial Counts</title>
      <link>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/bacterialcounts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 22:52:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dservgun.github.io/posts/bacterialcounts/</guid>
      <description>Bacterial counts at VP-003. In order to determine whether Chlorine released during the bio-remediation of TCE/PCE is a limiting factor, we measured the bacterial counts at two points seperated by 70 hours.
  3/23/2020 - 14, 800, 000 CFU/ml
     3/25/2020 - 15, 300, 000 CFU/ml
     The sustained population count indicates that increase in levels of Chlorine due to bio-remediation of PCE and TCE are not impacting the bacterial population in VaporRemed.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>